I'm happy to introduce Keith Gormley and
Zach Foster who will be here who will be
talking to us about credential and the
bringer challenges
campaign um Keith Gormley is the
director of social media management at
credential and he has been since
December of
2012 previously he was the managing
director and Lead social media
strategist with Abrams research and
Abrams media working on GE Ritz Carlton
Microsoft and AMC and Keith holds a MERS
in digital communication from Pepperdine
University Zack Foster is the brand
strategy director at droga 5 responsible
for commun communication strategy on
behalf of credentials Master brand
initiatives last year this translated
into the birth of day one a breakthrough
retirement focused campaign that was one
of Ted's 10 Ted's 10 adsw worth
spreading and a recipient of the golds
integrated Lion at con before droga Zach
worked for San Francisco agency's
Venable Bell could be Silverstein
working on campaigns for Audi Intel
Chevrolet among others so please welcome
Keith and
Zach thank
you I've been working since I was about
16 you know one job or the
other the moment I could uh access the
retirement plan I just became firm about
it I'm done I'm I'm out of here you know
it's like it just hits you fast you know
you start thinking about what's really
important
[Music]
here welcome um I think a lot of you may
be familiar with the the day one work um
it's been around for about a year and a
half 2012 for credential was definitely
the the year of day one and has done a
lot inter and externally to just shift
the conversation um we we created about
19 of those documentaries and short and
long form content um and they've uh you
know done a lot of great things um just
in you know their new Day One funds um
the vernaculars changed internally um I
think it's been very successful in the
in the context of just showing a
different side of retirement I think
there was a trend for a while showing a
very dramatized view of you know people
on yachts and sailing around on beaches
and salt and pepper haired models
feeding each other pie um and I think
that um we've just tried to be honest
and present things in a a genuine
authentic grounded way um and uh We've
uh decided to um keep that as a as a big
component of uh our bringer challenges
work um but have started to migrate into
a new um
Direction do you want to say anything
else no I got yeah um so look it's no
secret that credential is late to the
social media game um I think for us any
number of factors caused this delay
everything from regulatory to compliance
to uh Human Resources human capital um
but originally I don't think it was a
critical missing piece for us until we
launched the day one campaign um just
put aside the fact that the content
you've seen here in the 19 documentaries
were so emotional um that emotion made
them very
sharable uh but the truth is we didn't
have a vehicle to seed this content in
the social space to make it as sharable
as it could have been uh but think about
the website itself um Zach didn't
mention this but on the site there is a
way for you to actually share your day
one story so you can post a picture of
the day one of your retirement you could
tell us a little bit of that story and
then it's sharable from there um but
getting to the people to that site to to
make that effort to share was a little
bit difficult not having a credential
social media presence um
and our call to action to get to that
site was
broadcast um since these are very
personal stories think about the last
time you went to a website a brand
website and shared a personal story with
that brand or with people sharing there
it just doesn't happen you don't do it
very often uh unless you're entering a
contest or something and look we're not
Nike and we're not Oreo we're not going
to give you you know free T-shirt If you
share your story with us um these kinds
of stories are made for social media
people go to Facebook in particular uh
to share stories like this um so I think
it was at that point that we realized
that social was going to be helpful for
us in this kind of campaign and it
helped us move that needle forward so
that we could be a player in the social
space um that's why in late January this
year we launched our Facebook presence
for bring your challenges and really the
day one campaign helped us to uh educate
how we would move forward with the new
Campaign which we're going to talk about
now so I think in the context of Social
and
the the theme of today being allaround
content I think uh we're going to share
a lot of content today uh so you'll get
a little entertainment uh maybe a little
knowledge maybe a few Chuckles um but I
think uh day one did a great job in in
showing the the Endo uh showing day one
of potentially a longer retirement but
under the bring your challenges platform
we felt like there was an opportunity to
dig into the challenges that people face
on the road to day one um so you know in
the category there's a lot of talk
around financial literacy which um I
think there's there's a lot of work out
there um I think it's sort of a
saturated term I think we we had an
ambition to go sort of a layer deeper um
and a step further I think the first uh
sort of source of inspiration is
probably one that a lot of you all are
interested in um which are the fields
like uh behavioral economics Behavioral
Science neuro economics um we just sort
of inundated ourselves with intelligence
from these fields and really started to
get behind the reasons why people make
the predictably irrational decisions
that they do excuse the uh phrase um and
I think we we had a we had a feeling and
and we saw in some research that um this
idea of bring your challenges this idea
of tackling your biggest Financial
challenges we felt like you can't tackle
your challenges until you first
understand them um from inside out and
so this was sort of our jumping off
point uh for a lot of the new
work another important piece for us was
um we we thought it was really important
to Loop in a a credible narrator so
someone who lives and breathes this
stuff every day um won't name names but
there you know there are Brands out
there in this category that you know tap
people from the Hollywood world I think
that works some of the time um I think
that with the themes that we wanted to
explore in this campaign is really
important to get someone from this world
um to to speak on these subjects to be
our voice um so we found Dan Gilbert
after pretty exhaustive search he's a
professor of psychology at Harvard he's
a best-selling author um great on camera
um and uh Dan in addition to being an
expert on all things happiness related
was also doing a lot of interesting work
in the fields of longevity so the fact
that we are living significantly longer
um
and our inability to picture our future
selves and and that's part of the reason
we can't plan today because there's this
disconnect between ourselves and
ourselves in the future so Dan was a
great source and you know longevity as a
topic is nothing new it's been around um
for a while it's been in the
consciousness of American culture for a
while uh Nat Geo I don't know if anyone
has seen their most recent issue but
it's all around longevity with a series
of babies with the line this baby to
120 um you know times covered it if you
guys have seen Transcendent man you
should although it's terrifying uh Ray
kurtwell basically says we're all going
to be immortal um but it's a really
fascinating subject and one that we felt
like needed to be brought into the
consciousness of the financial World um
and so that was the first task that we
gave to Dan Gilbert and worked with him
to develop a a demonstration an
experiment of
sorts 65 years old when that became the
official retirement age back when my dad
was a kid life expectancy was about 61
not much of a retirement huh luckily
things have changed to see how we went
out and asked people a simple question
how old is the oldest person you've
known the oldest person I really know is
probably my grandfather he's 93 94 104
years old then we gave them each a
sticker and had them show
us
soon we learned a lot of us have known
someone who's lived well into their '90s
and that's a great thing but even though
we're living longer one thing that
hasn't changed the official retirement
age the question is how do you make sure
you have the money you need to enjoy all
of these
[Music]
[Applause]
years all right so this first a during
the Super Bowl this year hopefully you
have seen it if not then since then um
so after looking at this you can see
that there's a clear way for us to
extend this into the digital space and
into social uh people were placing
stickers for the oldest person they've
known uh and we wanted to make sure that
others could be able to do that as well
in digital because you obviously weren't
all in Austin to help us to fill that
wall um we developed a sticker's micro
site uh where anyone could log in and
place a sticker but also they could tell
us a story wor about uh the person the
oldest person that they have known so
what is the advice that they had given
you or what is their secret to living so
long uh we had three experiences uh all
filtering back to the same wall uh so
you could access via the microsite you
could access on your mobile so there's a
a fully mobile experience uh we're
seeing a lot of second screen
participation uh but then also on
Facebook so this was a great way for us
to uh launch into Facebook to have our
page but also an extension uh through a
tab on the Facebook page where you could
then dedicate your sticker but also
share that with others so it could
spread and it's more about sharing the
story it's not about sharing this with
credential it's about sharing the story
of the oldest person that you have known
uh and letting other people know about
that all the while you starting to think
about longevity and you're starting to
see this visual representation take
place on this digital wall that lots of
people know people who have lived into
their 90s even into their hundreds uh we
had people dedicate stickers for those
119 1208 so uh really great stories
started develop to develop there uh but
what we started to see also is that
using social media so we now have this
Facebook page we our call to action from
social was to go to this microsite and
dedicate your sticker there but in
asking that we found that more people
were actually using Facebook to tell us
those stories so our call to action was
go to this micro site dedicate your
sticker but they would write in the
comments on Facebook tell us that story
they would tell us who the oldest person
they knew was and I think again this
goes back to the idea that people are
just more comfortable on Facebook and
social sharing their stories there
rather than going to a website now the
micro site has worked we've got a lot of
really great stickers over 2,000 in a
short period of time with some really
good stories and it has a really great
visual representation aspect of it I
think uh that data visualization again
it helps you start to think about
longevity but we saw the most robust
stories taking place actually on
Facebook and in Social so again the the
quality you can see here of the
engagement that we were getting on
social and and Facebook was really great
um I think we would have expected that
would have been some negative things
maybe some comments that weren't
appropriate but most of what we saw were
that people were really proud of the
people that they have known that have
lived so long um so again social was
really where we saw the best
engagement yeah so this was sort of the
first stage in in getting the
conversation going uh around longevity
and I think that uh we work closely with
with Keith and his team to create a a
library of content to spark additional
conversation around longevity so you
know little factoids like you know the
first person to live to 150 is alive
today um those stories that Keith was
talking about repurposing them in the
social space we did a deal with Jeopardy
to actually have longevity uh oriented
questions featured um on their online
platform and that National Geographic um
theme that we saw before we also worked
with them to develop an an online tool
to allow you to upload a photo of your
favorite baby uh to be on the cover
that's my niece right there um so you
know the the first month first month or
two was really about sparking that
conversation and and and starting to
associate PR especially with this idea
of since we are living longer we better
prepare for a longer retirement and
these stats and statistics that we've
been posting things like uh scientists
say the first person to live 2 150 has
already been born these kinds of things
are a little bit shocking and
controversial when you first see them
but they're incredibly sharable um sure
we do broadcast them from our Facebook
Facebook page but we found that these
types of statistics and facts are
sharable between users so for a brand
like credential there's nothing more
valuable to us than when one user shares
with another rather than when us as a
brand we share it with the user talk a
little bit about social media
advertising for Brands it's something
that we just can't avoid it's part of
what we have to do in order to
participate in the social space uh but I
think the thing that's encouraging here
is that it's actually helped us be more
efficient uh with our targeting rather
than just broadcasting our message and
our content out to a wide net so uh
collecting followers and trying to reach
as many people with the message what
we've been able to do is target people
that we know will be interested in the
content that we have to put out uh
especially the content that we're going
to be talking about today with the new
bring your challenges website and this
behavioral Finance content we know that
there's a thirst for this type of
content out there and using social media
advertising we've been able to Target
those groups who have already shown that
they're interested in this content uh
and then we're less likely to see uh
number one anything negative because of
our social advertising uh but also
people are far more likely to engage
with our content they're more likely to
share it comment on it because we know
that they'll be interested in it so we
launched our Twitter feed just about two
or three weeks ago um and now what we're
seeing in Social is that rather than
this just being a oneway conversation
with us and the user we're starting to
see it as a two-way conversation
particularly on Twitter um happens a
little bit on Facebook but much more on
Twitter uh we're able to be accessible
to the fan um so it's not just that
we're sending out a mess message and
they're liking it or commenting on it
we're actually seeing fans engage with
us and ask us questions uh so we try our
best to answer as many of those
questions as possible and that to us is
a meaningful engagement they're
interacting with our brand uh not as a
brand but as an individual at a
company also in addition to just
interacting and answering questions
we're able to reach out proactively to
fans who have mentioned maybe they don't
know that we have a social presence
particularly on Twitter maybe they've
mentioned just the presedential name
maybe they've talked about one of our
websites or our micro sites or our
broadcast commercial we can reach out to
them and say thank you for your comment
uh take a look here for more information
here's our new website there's lots more
great content there uh we have a lot of
people talking about Dan Gilbert who's
our spokesperson uh the videos that
they're seeing airing on broadcast we're
able to reach out to them and they don't
know that we have a presence as
credential and we could say we've got
even more great content more behavioral
psychologists and experts on our website
feel free to take a look at those as
well this has also been very helpful for
us with our paid media outside of social
um what we're seeing is that this paid
these paid engagements plus social media
really equal earned impressions for us
uh we had a big takeover of the New York
Times uh this was in early April uh it
was a banner ad but believe it or not
this was actually received very well and
uh spread across social like crazy the
banner ad is not dead apparently um this
was a unique Banner ad though this was
uh tapping into the New York Times API
so you could enter your birthday and
then see uh the cover of the New York
Times on the day of your birthday uh we
were seeing lots of people share this we
also integrated within the banner ad
once you shared it you also shared our
Twitter handle with that so presented by
presedential byc the Twitter handle had
only been live for about a week and we
actually gained about 2,000 followers
due to this all organic um just because
we had included that in there uh we also
had articles by masteral and click click
Z and digiday and that really helps and
um obviously that that helped to show
people that we had you know the new
Twitter handle but also that this was a
really interesting engagement and the
content was positive all around so I
think similar to the to the banner and
and and just the nature of the the work
that we're doing with Dan Gilbert it's
really important that we um a lot of our
work is very action oriented we just
don't we don't want to just go out in
the world and talk about longevity talk
about the fact that people are living
longer and you need to prepare we
actually want to act um and so I think
like Dan going out in the world and
collecting stickers and doing the stem
ministration um we've been working with
some of the world's leading uh
behavioral psychologists neuro
neuroeconomist and so on um to dig
deeper on this topic and we worked with
one um really interesting guy named Adam
alter who's a professor of psychology at
NYU um and we uh developed the first
episode of what's going to be a longer
documentary series called brain is to
blame uh which dives into uh not just
the decisions we make but why we make
them the fact that maybe it's not our
fault that we make that we're making
these decisions maybe our brain is to
blame for a lot of the predictably
irrational things that we do so I want
to share that with you
[Music]
today hi there hi quick question for you
instead of getting your coffee would you
mind giving me a couple of bucks towards
my retirement are you kidding I wouldn't
even think about
itny for your retirement my re you can
give me a couple of bucks of my
retirement guy I don't know just a few
bucks would be a good start I think I
think I really want the coffee you
really want the coffee all right no
worries not surprisingly people weren't
willing to donate to a strangers a
retirement fund and yet that's exactly
the challenge we're facing every day
when saving for our own retirement why
is that research has shown that we think
of our older selves as strangers and it
turns out our brain is to
blame you see when you think about
yourself this part of the brain lights
up brightly
when you think about a stranger it dims
and when you think about yourself in the
future the same thing happens it's like
you're a stranger to
yourself and as we saw at the coffee
truck nobody wants to give money to a
stranger right now I'm not putting any
money away I'm just kind of focusing on
the here and now I have not planned
whatsoever for my retirement can I
picture myself in retirement no no I
can't the challenge is how do we connect
with our older selves to make retirement
more Vivid and real researchers have
used a number of techniques but we
wanted to try something new something a
little different so we brought together
12 random people and one
hypnotherapist our goal to see if we
could get people to actually feel like
they're retired and to find out if that
would motivate them to prepare more for
their future welcome I do not think I
can be
hypnotized probably not no not at all so
we're here today to consider this whole
idea aide of what it would be like if
now you were already retired and how can
you do that CH you're not retired yet
right but I'm going to show you how
we're going to start the process
off gently let your eyes close when
you're ready and let's see where we
go first the group was brought into a
relaxed
State then they were guided through a
series of visualizations
an hour later they woke to life in
retirement 1 2
3 begin to come back to
me and when you're ready I want you to
draw a picture on that paper of you now
that you're
[Music]
retired I saw myself as a teacher and as
put myself of teaching
kids basically it was most of me writing
a book and then I put little X's cuz I
had like sort of signed a contract to
I'm still aggressive and wild but okay
for this handful of people our
experiment turned retirement From A
Distant event into something very real
did I encounter My Future Self yes I did
I was
terrific it was surprising because um he
was he was younger than than I expected
him to be
actually I had hair so I guess it's a
cure for baldness in the future like
future didn't seem like future it's it
felt more tangible I didn't think of my
wife until later on and I thought I
should put her in there no comment for
me there are a lot of ways to connect
with our older selves but what if we
started by just thinking about our lives
at that age would that help us see our
futur s not as strangers but as us in
retirement would that change the way we
prepare for
[Music]
tomorrow I feel like I need to do more
like there's a fire under me more now
financially My Future Self was in a
totally different place than I am so I
feel like I need to learn how to kind of
save more and spend less so I can like
live bigger
[Music]
later
really what your
retirement thank
you so obviously you can imagine the um
challenge of selling in an idea like
we're going to work with a hypnotist uh
to an company like credential but and
obviously we we don't want to be known
as the the brand that that hypnotized
people into believing that they should
save more for retirement but I think the
point here is um credential as as a
brand um and the work that we're trying
to do is just aimed at getting people to
think a little bit differently take a
moment to just picture your future self
we may not be able to hypnotize everyone
but the fact that we have this
disconnect with our future selves and
there are ways to get a little bit
closer to that person is just one step
uh among many to to to get us to take
action today I think we we use social as
as a tool to not only distribute this
content but also as a learning tool um
so you know we we plan to make a lot
more of this content uh in the coming
months uh and next year so um and so
when we put this stuff out in the world
uh we can create that two-way dialogue
that that Keith was talking about we can
get feedback on this content we can get
an understanding of how this is
motivating people to act and that
informs the content that we create next
yeah I think you can tell by taking a
look at that that video that it's
difficult to get people to think about
themselves in the future and their
longevity it's just not a topic we want
to naturally think about in our
day-to-day lives so social for us is a
challenge in that the content that we
put out needs to help people to start to
think about that it's an uncomfortable
topic to think about so we're doing our
best to make it as engaging and
interesting as possible so in Social our
key performance indicators are that
engagement so are people sharing are
they retweeting are they commenting and
liking and we take that data and we look
at we've positioned that content in
Social so uh what was the text what was
the copy did we use a link did we use an
image did we use a video did it work is
there a better way for us to do it to
present this content so that the next
time someone sees it they're considering
these very important uh topics when they
see our content so we see social and our
content as a cycle as sort of a one
feeding the other sure we use our
Facebook page and our Twitter feed and
our our LinkedIn company page to seed
this content to get it out there and
broadcast but once they're there and
they've been driven to our micro site we
want them to share the content that's
there I mean we aren't hooked up to show
you the site now with Wi-Fi but uh feel
free to take a look at it it's bring
your challenges.com it has tons of
content like what we've been showing you
so videos interactive uh snackable
pieces of content uh that we call them
uh really just helping you to start
thinking about all of these different
behavioral channels which we're going to
talk about so they each feeds the other
the site feeds into social because you
can share the items but then also we're
seeding content there and hoping that
they'll come to the
site and I think everything that we
create on uh the site that kei's talking
about uh which is bring your
challenges.com we've we've tried to
launch an initiative uh and we call it
the challenge lab and it lives in bring
your challenges.com but every piece of
content that's housed on there is built
to be modular so we're not relying on
people to come to the site and you know
consume all of our content the content
is built to be out in the world in the
places where our audience is and I think
one of the unique things about the site
is that we've broken it down into um the
five most pressing human behavior
challenges and we've talked to a lot of
experts to really nail down if you were
to say you know five things what are the
five most important things that are
getting in the way of preparing for our
our financial Futures what would they be
and we've narrowed them down down to
five things and that's sort of how the
is structured so a lot of the content
that you've been seeing around longevity
is in this idea of the IE might live how
long challenge um so the fact that there
is this disconnect with our future
selves and we need to prepare for this
longer U retirement and that's not
something that we're sort of built to do
second is the allo it later challenge
which is pretty self-explanatory uh it's
all around sort of the forces of
procrastination why we procrastinate how
we can overcome
procrastination um and how we can get
going today on on planning better uh
third is the I want it now challenge
which again is pretty self-explanatory
but uh it it deals with how we um you
know overcome our instant gratification
urges how we temper those urges those um
those needs to consume now uh I just
can't resist you'll notice the bubble
bubble rep um visual I just can't resist
is really just understanding how our
emotions impact our financial decisions
so the fact that we by nature are social
creatures we are herd animals if you
will and um you know a lot of times the
wisdom of the crowds leades us leads us
to great places but not always and then
the the final one is the it won't happen
to me challenge uh which is um deals a
lot with the ideas of optimism bias and
invulnerability bias the fact that
invulnerability bias I think is
fascinating which just says that we uh
actually believe that ourselves and our
families are less at risk than a
stranger for something bad happening to
us which is just a an insane um concept
I think optimism bias the idea that we
as Americans especially are optimistic
um people uh but that often gets in the
way of preparing being more prudent
about our our futures and taking the
steps necessary to to get
there and uh if we had the site we would
bring that up uh now but like we're
diving into the the financial
conversation a bit of a different way we
also present our information in a very
different way so instead of just saying
the fact that one in three babies born
today will live to 100 we actually
wanted to play with typography and and
designed to present these things in a
unique compelling way so on the site you
have these rotating um facts and
snackables as we call them so uh you
know more babies are B uh born today are
more likely to have blonde hair or blue
eyes or play the drums than um they're
more likely to live to 100 than do those
things you know what would you have seen
if if you were 150 years old today you
would have seen the presidency of
Abraham Lincoln and the invention of the
the movie camera we also have a um a
function called timeline of Innovations
which covers some you know legitimate
some sort of fun things that since since
the beginning of time that have impacted
our longevity so the fact that in the
1800s duels were a thing and so our
longevity suffered because of that um
but in the 1900s you know uh water
purification was was big and so our
longevity um spiked um so we've had a
lot of fun with this and just delivering
information and content in new ways um
another example of that is a a new video
that just launched yesterday um that
just gives a little bit of a nod to some
of the forces that lead to a longer life
some uh more predictable and um
legitimate than they're all legitimate
but uh we had a little fun with it um
just in the
tone studies show you have a better
chance of living longer if you eat a
Mediterranean diet drink a glass of red
wine every day enjoy
gardening live on a
mountain or are a
woman you'll live longer if you work
near indoor plants are
Hispanic and floss
often if you live in the country do lots
of yoga are a married person and have
four or more children if you a
occasionally indulge in dark chocolate
and are
right-handed if you get along with your
mother have a younger mother have a name
that starts with a and if you have a pet
so it's simple if you happen to be a
buff right-handed yodling country Mama's
girl enaile named Anna with a green
thumb a sweet tooth a full house and an
unwavering respect for proper dental
hygiene then you could live
[Music]
longer
so and I think the other thing to note
is that um that obviously looks very
different than the brain is to blame
stuff and that's very intentional and I
think the part of the role that social
is playing is to get different things
out in the world that look a little bit
differently that function a little bit
differently and start to get a sense of
what's working and what's not and again
it goes back to knowing our audience
that not every piece of content will
work well for the entire audience
audence we're trying to reach so we're
segmenting it a little bit more uh with
specific contents for specific
audiences the other thing that we've
done and and to the earlier point of uh
a lot of the literature that I I'm happy
to give a list although I'm sure you
guys have read all the books but um
we've dug into just some interesting
compelling uh facts from Behavioral
Science studies and just made um
interesting sort of typography Centric
um visuals that are you know very
sharable so the fact that you know we
have these great intentions and we buy
all this fresh prod produce but onethird
of all produce goes uneaten so the fact
that you know just knowing that we have
good intentions in other parts of our
lives uh or the fact that a tear jerker
cost you more than a comedy so the fact
that there are studies out there they
they track people that come out of a a
sappy sad movie come out of a comedy and
the people coming out of the sad sappy
movie actually buy more uh right
afterwards than uh those out of a comedy
so just getting in touch and getting
being more aware of how our emotions are
impacting our our financial and and
buying decisions is just um inherently
interesting and I think uh one of the
things you may be wondering is um you
know how do we how do we come back
around um and I think that one of the
things about bring your challenges.com
and a lot of the con all the content
that we put out in the world is you're
never more than one click away from uh
Financial action so you can always you
know after the brain is to blame you can
always click through to find out more
about Retirement Solutions Insurance
Solutions investing Solutions you can
always click to find a financial adviser
you can always um you know get a video
breakdown a little bit more about why
it's important to have income that lasts
over the course of your retirement or
you know hear from a credential thought
leader um about these topics um and I
think in addition to the the thought
leaders that we've tapped from the
presedential side it's also been an
amazing process to work with some of the
world's uh leading experts in some of
these fields that we've talked about
before and been really cool to converse
with them um and they're they're just
sort of willing to offer guidance and
contribute to the campaign for free uh
just because we're they live it every
day and they're thrilled that um someone
from this community is is acting upon it
so we have a a section on the site
called the Roundtable um which right now
has uh six experts um from everywhere
from Yale to Carnegie melon to Harvard
um and they're just creating original
sort of blog style posts and the first
topic was what are the biggest uh
behavioral challenges that we Face uh in
planning for a longer retirement and so
you know one person wrote about um the
modern version of keeping up with the
Joneses and the psychological impact of
that another wrote about you know the
you see the image of the guy boxing his
brain and the fact that it's just not a
fair fight and there are certain things
that we should understand about
ourselves that can help us plan better
and this is this is going to be sort of
an evergreen um constantly updated
section of the site that can be
syndicated out to different Media
Partners and our social platforms so we
have a lot of hopes for this to um
flourish in the in the near
future and then the last thing uh I
wanted to uh leave you with um is just
something that that launched yesterday
and some of you may be uh very familiar
with one of the most famous uh
psychological studies ever which was the
marshmallow test um and we we decided to
um just come at it uh you know a little
bit of a modern remake of of this idea
which is a new piece of content um that
you can find
[Music]
online going in
here and we actually we have a treat you
like marshmallows yeah yeah do you want
to have a seat let's get
comfortable the deal is you can eat this
marshmallow now or you can wait until I
come back and I'll give you two
marshmallows if you decide to change
your mind that's fine okay I'm waiting
okay I'm going to push you in a little
bit more
oh I'll be back in a few minutes
[Music]
uhhuh
you want to have two marshmallows yeah
then don't eat the
[Music]
marshmallow
hey Lola how'd you do good I was waiting
you were waiting good job here's your
second marshmallow thank you you didn't
eat your marshmallow now so you get
another one that took a little bit too
long I know I'm sorry do you think your
mom or dad would eat the first
marshmallow or do you think they would
wait like you did well my dad would eat
the first marshmallow and my mom would
patiently wait I think my dad would
would a do
away I think she would eat the
marshmallow I think she would like try
the like try the best as she could to
wait I chose to wait
because cuz um
patience patience is
[Music]
good
thank you thank
you so we do have some time for
questions if anyone has them yes um uh I
would just saying that it was a
wonderful presentation which I'm sure we
all agree uh uh what what I was curious
about is a lot of the work that you're
doing is C is is is very um personalized
to different channels and different
audiences and this has to be very uh
labor intensive so I was wondering I
mean compared to traditional advertising
uh traditional media where you do one
thing and just broadcast it so how have
you had to restructure the number of
people you have working both on the
agency side and on the client side in
order to meet this kind of
challenge well I think it's a challenge
that anyone that runs a social media
program faces because you're always
starred for Content you need things to
publish and when you start to become too
predictable and the content becomes the
same that's when you lose your audience
and you risk you run the risk of them
ignoring you or when they see your posts
they just sort of glaze over them so
it's certainly a challenge for us I
think even getting into the social space
for a financial services company takes a
huge huge effort it takes a team of
people uh because there are so many
considerations everything from
compliance and regulation to Legal
approvals for all of this content that
goes out um so it's been a long process
and I think that's why it took us as
long as it did to get here but
everything came together I think with
our work with droga 5 internal in
getting that content I think that was a
big part of it and keeping that content
fresh but then also internally
organizing so many groups of people and
Human Resources so getting teams of
people in order to number one be
available to post to see everything that
comes in so comments from users making
sure we're responding in a quick manner
uh customer service issues and then
knowing who should be contacted in case
of which I mean we're a big business we
have a lot of different things that we
do at credential uh Insurance retirement
annuities really across the board so
knowing who's appropriate to respond to
which kind of comment all these things
had to come together uh so it was really
about having a plan and the plan was
first getting the people on board with
second and then having the content all
of these things kind of came together at
the same
time one of the things that's
interesting is you're clearly are a big
organization and just interested in how
you involved your people in it it must
be a fantastic opportunity to get staff
engagement stuff like that up could you
talk a little bit about
that yeah I mean I I think one of the
one of the interesting things that
happened when we collectively brought
this Insight in this campaign idea to
the leadership team at presedential and
a lot of people over there is they the
presedential people feel like they've
been doing this work for a long time uh
they feel like they've been you know
they've been around for 137 years
studying human nature and um they
they're a risk management companies so
they've been studying the way that
people you know approach risk for a long
long time they've just never made it
consumer facing so I think it was a
little bit uh easier of a road to sell
in this idea in this case just because
it was so true to who credential has
been for a long time um and it's been
it's been fun to watch people rally
around the concept and uh I think
there's going to be an opportunity to to
to Loop in more credential thought
leaders who have had expertise and
Intelligence on this type of stuff to
come out and and be a new voice for the
brands yeah and I think if you look at
the core of the content it's really kind
of geeky and nerdy stuff and I think the
people in our company saw that and they
were like wow you're speaking our
languages is great and not only that
you've made it consumer friendly you've
made it so that other people outside of
just our Financial Services Group can
understand it they can grasp it and we
can get our message across about
longevity and uh you know all these
other channels that we're
approaching hi it's a two-part question
first of all brilliant campaign I'm
actually a fan of the ads before I
realized that you were it was connected
to you so it's a thrilled to meet you uh
two things um first of all can you tell
me a little bit about um how you
assemble your team for the this campaign
because it sounds like you basically
built it from scratch how you the
logistics around doing that and getting
Buy in and finally talk a little bit
about how um the marketing people and
the corporate coms people if they work
together how you made that work and who
did what sure I think and this again is
part of why it took us quite a while to
get into the social space because we
weren't sure who should be handling that
should it be corporate Communications
should it be marketing should it be
someone else I think the answer is that
it should be a hybrid of everybody so
the process was getting everybody on
board understanding what our processes
will be we have uh 140 page document
which I call our Bible it's really it
lists out everything you could possibly
think of that we would need to do in the
social space so uh how do we respond to
a comment or when should something be
deleted should things be deleted uh do
we retweet uh our own internal people so
we've got thought leaders who have their
own Twitter handles should we be
promoting them uh should we be
retweeting Dan Gilbert who's our sponsor
sponsor or spokesman excuse me um so a
lot of these things had to be worked out
in advance so the easiest answer to that
is that we had to plan long in advance
before anything went live as far as
building the team in addition to
building the immediate team so the
people who run the day-to-day which was
really just a staffing issue I mean
there's lots of young people who are so
excited about social and they get social
so it was easy to find people who are
interested in it and that can do it but
I think the bigger challenge was
assembling the credential team so
stakeholders from each of the different
businesses from corporate Communications
from legal and Advisory board so who are
the people who day-to-day will
communicate with myself and determine
what is the approach we should take
aside from a Content standpoint which is
sort of the easy part we've got so much
great content it's easy for us to
publish on this schedule and we've got
plenty to publish but what should our
approach be how should we handle
ourselves in Social defining that brand
image in the social space does that
answer it does but could you tell me
just how large a staff do you have sure
I've got a staff of five total but
that's just my immediate team and then
our social media advisory team is you
know 30 people and we meet you know once
a week to go over how things have gone
what do our statistics look like what
should we do differently so there are
lots of people interacting every day
about what our approach should be but
dayto day we've got uh you know five six
people who are watching 24 hours a day
everything that happens in our social
footprint so we started with Facebook
and they would watch Facebook using our
social tools to see what's happening
there as we we added Twitter we add
LinkedIn we had YouTube We turned
comments on for YouTube suddenly we've
got a lot more to watch and we need more
eyes to watch it mhm
thanks
project I just wanted to know um in the
process of actually assembling this
communication strategy uh was there
consideration for how do I make this
ownable to your brand to credential
brand and if so what was that point and
if not you know was it the bet that uh
you know the creative idea behind that
was striking that by leveraging the
right social media Vehicles you would
break through and kind of be there first
before other brands or what happened
there it's kind of my interest yeah it's
a good good question um I think we
you know we're not the first brand to
talk about behavioral Finance by any by
any means um I think that um we we
looked out in the world and it it felt
like no one was focusing all their
efforts on this field of Behavioral
Science and why we make the decisions we
do um I think that first and foremost we
wanted to crack getting the best
possible content um out there um and
making sure that the fit was right with
credential um and I think
uh maybe part of it was uh first mover
Advantage you know and I think brand
brand tracking will tell us that um
but uh yeah I mean I think I think day
one also helped a lot uh the fact that
over the last year and a half um at
least to some respect we credential has
become known uh a little bit for being
just a more human uh down toe authentic
brand that you know hears from real
people that have real anxieties about
retirement and I think that a lot of
this stuff is obviously rooted in in in
human beings and human beings behavior
um so I think that more and more we're
trying to build those equities around
credential as just a a really human
brand um so that's sort of what I'd say
yeah and I think the time is right too
for this content uh with the way that
the economy has gone and the way the
market fluctuates and the way people
think about their finances is different
now than it was five or six years ago so
telling this story from a human
perspective and U talking about real
people uh has been I think a good
approach for
us other
questions do you have plans to carry
this down to a local level for your
field forc to utilize these assets
that's I think that's a great question
um and the keynote speaker mentioned a
little bit about this the importance of
the people who are on the ground
actually carrying out your message um
again this goes back to a Regulatory
Compliance it's a difficult thing for us
to have registered reps on social media
but we're working towards it we have
pilot programs out there that are
testing different software tools that
allow us to keep track of everything uh
recordkeeping is a very difficult thing
for us to make sure that not only are we
keeping track and Reporting on what
they've put out but before they put it
out we want to make sure it's
appropriate it's proper it's
representing our brand uh but I think
that's speaks to a bigger and a larger
question about how do you develop a
master brand campaign and then have it
funnel through to each of your
businesses and then to the people who
are actually doing the work day-to-day
so it's uh a challenge but it's
something we're definitely working on
and thinking about uh from a social
perspective I think LinkedIn is the
perfect place for that and I'm not just
saying it because we're here I think
it's most people most professionals have
LinkedIn profiles you have the ability
out to broadcast content and share
content to share your perspective and to
share the credential perspective so I
think it's a good place and that's where
we've started um and I think Facebook is
a good extension of that possibly
Twitter for more influencer thought
leadership kind of content U but we're
getting there we're working on
it how many people are authorized to
tweet uh
to yeah so myself and then uh one person
that works alongside of me and that's
for our corporate account we also have a
account for our nonprofit arm credential
Spirit of community Awards and they have
two people that can tweet there uh and
then we also have a corporate
Communications account that's really
more about um news and and earnings and
that kind of thing and there are two or
three people there um but as far as for
our account we've got two uh but then we
do have people who are able to monitor
that all day every day and and we have
escalation processes where they're
sending the content through so that the
right person sees it but we try to
that's part of our risk mitigation it's
keeping it to as few people as possible
not having it on your phone so that if
you know staffers out partying and they
leave their phone by accident at the bar
someone can't tweet from our account I
mean these are things that we're seeing
people are hacking into accounts and you
the thing with the AP and Jeep and you
can go down the list of brands that have
had these kinds of things
happen constantly changing the password
and making sure that very few people
have access is a very important thing
for us and it's things are changing
constantly with the platforms and the
way people access them so we are having
to change our approach constantly and I
think being fluid is
important thank you it was great
campaign loved it um just wanted to find
out from the agency side and how you
guys approach behavioral Finance I mean
it's not a topic you can easily approach
uh you know how many planners you guys
and sort of like your the structure you
had from so just in internal structure
or okay um I mean I think we we have a
pretty lean team um at droga uh they're
we have um I guess two two strategists
on the account we have a couple of
creative teams uh we have an account
management staff um and I think from a
Behavioral Science standpoint it you
know it's you can't you can't um you
can't miss it it's it's out in the world
it's everywhere you know Dan Arelli is
sort of the The Godfather of Behavioral
economics and I think we as a team just
started to read more um about these
topics and just you know pick up books
in the airport uh read blogs whatever
you know whatever we could do and I
think it was a good little um petri dish
uh within droga 5 to just see you know a
designer for instance suddenly start to
geek out on behavioral Finance it's just
sort of a beautiful thing um and I think
um I think seeing you know we we work at
an ad agency where Finance you know
sifting through a 401k packet is just
the the worst possible thing you could
endure um and so I think seeing uh the
effect that this type of stuff was
having on just our people and suddenly
people were enrolling and upping their
contributions in their 401k and reading
more about how they can prepare for
their finances was a good little tiny uh
you know little test study of whether
this stuff could actually resonate with
consumers so I think we we embraced it
uh wholeheartedly and I think it didn't
take long to um see that the pr people
were already they were already sort of
spinning their wheels on that um it
helps too that it's fun and you're
seeing it more often in uh pop culture
so with podcasts like Radio Lab and This
American Life even dives into that kind
of thing you see it on TV you see it in
books everywhere obviously these airport
books are much more popular but Malcolm
Gladwell Tipping Point things like that
they coming to the mainstream and you're
reading them and you don't even realize
you're reading about things that we're
talking about anyway so I think younger
staff especially have touched on those
things based on pop culture or maybe
they studied it in school and then it's
interesting to them it's not flipping
through a 401k packet or you know the
really nitty-gritty stuff so
approachability I think is the
key back
[Music]
here first amazing work I absolutely
love it how are you measuring all this
and proving out success and are you able
to tie to actual business
results that's a very good question I
think for us it's in Social it's about
awareness at this point eventually we'll
get to the point where we're more
targeted and we're participating in
business conversations about annuities
or life insurance um we're not a
consumer company in the sense that we
don't have a website where you can go
and click and purchase a life insurance
policy we're more B2B uh Financial
professional so our goal is to get you
to start thinking about these big topic
topics and then get you to see a
financial professional so that maybe you
can purchase one of our products through
a financial professional so making that
line and drawing that line from A to B
is difficult I think it's something
worth thinking of from a more practical
standpoint um our kpis are really about
engagement so are people interacting
with our content are they sharing it are
they retweeting it are they liking it as
a bit more passive maybe they're
commenting um are they going to our
micro sites and participating there are
they dedicating a sticker are they
watching our video um I think one of the
goals from my office at least is when
we're creating and seeding the content
in Social we want the message to be
self-contained we want it to be as it is
so that you don't have to do too much in
order to get the idea that we're trying
to get across so if it's posting a link
that's a second step you have to take so
if you see the post in your Facebook
Newsfeed and then you have to click
through to get the message across we may
have lost you we've lost certainly a lot
of people so if we're able to get that
awareness message and that get you to
think about longevity and think about
these different things with just the
message itself I think we've succeeded
so I hesitate to say that our only kpi
is clicking through and retweeting and
liking because I know that the way that
we've positioned the content is so that
it can be consumed in one piece even if
it's passive I think the the only other
thing to mention is um you know in
addition to the bulk of the content that
lives on bring your challenges which
we're we're watching closely engagement
metric tricks and interaction rates all
that kind of stuff we're also measuring
um what we're calling soft conversion so
um people linking through from content
like the marshmallow video to actual um
credential solution specific um content
um and those metrics thus far have been
pretty strong um and then in addition
like like any brand we watch brand
tracking pretty closely um so uh you
know we've we've seen really preliminary
stuff but uh we're going to be looking
close at some of the awareness metrics
and and early consideration stuff and
look I mean we're digital people so we
certainly sit at our desks and we post
something to Twitter or Facebook and
then we go to Google analytics real time
we see who's clicking through that's fun
for us but it's it's not at the end of
the day our number one
indicator on the micro site a challenge
we have is keeping the content Fresh So
how on the micro site one of the
challenges we have is keeping the
content fresh so how often are you
updating it and then is one what's
working the best you know thought
leadership versus
video yeah I mean I think uh at launch
there was you know unsurprisingly a big
burst of content so just to to get it up
and to get initial engagement but we
have a pretty full pipeline of content
that we plan to I mean depending on some
of the engagement metrics um we're going
to sort of it's going to be a bit of a
slow play probably every every month or
so we'll publish something new we just
had a a new um push of content that went
live last night and that consisted of
you know maybe four new pieces on the
site um but I think um the most
important thing we're doing now is just
looking at the numbers um and the types
of things that people are interacting
with how we should prioritize the
content um the type of things that are
working particularly well in Social um
so I think more than anything right now
it's a great learning phase but we do
have a ton of content coming um down the
down the
shoot thank you so much
everyone